vivo.sx 2019-12-11

# vıvo | Privacy Policy

#### Effective from January 26, 2019

This Privacy Policy applies between you, the User of this Website and VIVO ("us", "we", or "our"), the owner and provider of this Website. VIVO takes the privacy of your information very seriously. This webpage informs you about our use of any and all Data collected by us or provided by you in relation to your use of the Website. Please notice that this Privacy Policy applies only to the actions of VIVO and Users with respect to this Website. It does not extend to any websites that can be accessed from this Website including, but not limited to, any links we may provide to social media websites. 

This Privacy Policy should be read carefully and alongside in addition to our Terms and Conditions.

### Definitions and interpretation

In this Privacy Policy, the following definitions are used:

  * **Data**

collectively all information that you submit to VIVO via the Website. This definition incorporates, where applicable, the definitions provided in the Data Protection Laws;

  * **Data Controller**

for purposes of the applicable Data Protection Laws, VIVO is the "data controller" which means that VIVO determines the purposes for which, and the manner in which, your Data is processed;

  * **Data Protection Laws**

any applicable law relating to the processing of personal Data, including but not limited to the Directive 96/46/EC (Data Protection Directive) or the GDPR, and any national implementing laws, regulations and secondary legislation;

  * **GDPR**

the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679;

  * **Cookies**

a text file placed on your computer by this Website to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behavior information when you visit certain parts of the Website and/or when you use certain features of the Website;

  * **Website**

the website that you are currently using, vivo.sx, and any sub-domains of this site unless expressly excluded by the Terms and Conditions.

### What Data do we collect?

We may collect the following Data, which includes personal Data, from you:

  * **Personal identification information**

such as your name and e-mail address which only is applicable when you register an account with us.

  * **Usage information**

consisting of your IP address, web browser type and version, operating system, traffic pattern on how you interact with this Website like page views, navigation paths, length of visit as well as referral source. This information is always de-personalised including your IP address which is anonymised by either masking or cryptographically hashing it. 

### How do we collect your Data?

Most of the Data is provided directly by yourself or automatically on the technical basis of the Internet (IP) and Hypertext Transfer (HTTP) protocol. You may provide us additionally with Data when you voluntarily create a VIVO account, use or view this Website and its Service with or without an account, or when you contact us by using any of the forms on this Website. We do not share any of your Data with a third-party, but "Usage Data" of you may be collected by third-party websites, plug-ins or applications which we may include and use on this Website, like Yandex Metrica and several Advertising Networks. Please be aware that our Privacy Policy does not extend to these third-parties. 

### How will we use your Data?

We collect and use your Data exclusively for the purposes of optimizing our Website and improving our Service to deliver the best possible content. In particular this is neccessary to be able to manage your account and the Services we provide, along with displaying the right advertisement to you. 

We may use your Data for the above purposes if we deem it necessary to do so for our legitimate interests. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract or a Service between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract. 

### How do we store your Data?

VIVO securely stores your Data on our servers for which we took certain technical and organisational measures to safeguard them, like: 

  * the access to your account is controlled by a password and an e-mail address that is unique to you;
  * our servers software is being kept up to date to avoid security exploits and the access to the Data is protected by firewalls and login credentials.

Regarding the Data retention, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law, we will only hold your Data on our systems for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy or until you request that the Data be deleted.

### How do we use Cookies?

VIVO uses Cookies in a range of ways to improve your experience on our Website which includes keeping you signed in your account, to understand how you use our Website, keeping several preferences stored, e.g., which website language you have selected. We have carefully chosen these Cookies and has taken steps to ensure that your privacy is protected and respected at all times. For your information and understanding, you will be presented a message bar notifying you that this Website is using Cookies which are essential to provide you with a full functional Website and tailored Service. If you do not agree with that, you may not be able to use this Website. 

### What are your rights?

You have the following rights in relation to your Data:

  * **Right to access**

the right to request (i) copies of the information we hold about you at any time, or (ii) that we modify, update or delete such information. If we provide you with access to the information we hold about you, we will not charge you for this, unless your request is "manifestly unfounded or excessive." Where we are legally permitted to do so, we may refuse your request. If we refuse your request, we will tell you the reasons why. 

  * **Right to correct**

the right to have your Data rectified if it is inaccurate or incomplete.

  * **Right to erase**

the right to request that we delete or remove your Data from our systems.

  * **Right to restrict our use of your Data**

the right to restrict us from using your Data, under certain conditions.

  * **Right to data portability**

the right to request that we move, copy or transfer your Data.

  * **Right to object**

the right to object to our use of your Data including where we use it for our legitimate interests.

To make enquiries, exercise any of your rights set out above, or withdraw your consent to the processing of your Data (where consent is our legal basis for processing your Data), please contact us here.

### Transfers outside the European Economic Area

Data which we collect from you may be stored and processed in and transferred to countries outside of the European Economic Area (EEA). For example, this could occur if our servers are located in a country outside the EEA or one of our service providers is situated in a country outside the EEA. 

We will only transfer Data outside the EEA where it is compliant with data protection legislation and the means of transfer provides adequate safeguards in relation to your data, e.g. by way of data transfer agreement, incorporating the current standard contractual clauses adopted by the European Commission, or by signing up to the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework, in the event that the organisation in receipt of the Data is based in the United States of America. 

To ensure that your Data receives an adequate level of protection, we have put in place appropriate safeguards and procedures with the third parties we share your Data with. This ensures your Data is treated by those third parties in a way that is consistent with the Data Protection Laws.

### Changes to the Privacy Policy

VIVO reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy as we may deem necessary from time to time or as may be required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the Website and you are deemed to have accepted the terms of the Privacy Policy on your first use of the Website following the alterations.
